--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 猫呗
翻译: 影子
校对: 影子
阿加莎·克里斯蒂作品
无人生还
我爱你 我爱你...
I love you, I love you...
西里尔! 西里尔!
Cyril! Cyril!
伦敦 1939年8月
这个职位... 是秘书
The, er... position is for a secretary.
那中介就应该不会把我的名字给你
Then the agency shouldn't have given you my name.
我打字和速记的能力不够好
My typing and shorthand isn't good enough.
那就是助理
Assistant, then.
附带些次要的秘书任务
With some minor secretarial duties.
我把详细情况都发给她看了 她选了你
I sent her all the details. She chose you.
真的?
Really?
你是老师对吗?
You're a teacher?
是的 体育老师
Games mistress, yes.
老师都有很好的组织能力
Teachers are good at organising.
欧文太太要招待很多宾客
Mrs Owen is expecting a lot of guests.
确切位置在哪呢?
Whereabouts in the country?
德文海岸 士兵岛
The Devon coast. Soldier Island.
在海岸边?
The coast?
奥德丽一直都在和我念叨杂志上这事...
Audrey's been telling me about it from her magazines...
是吧 奥德丽?
haven't you, Audrey?
这座岛本该是一些好莱坞影星买下的
Some Hollywood film star was supposed to have bought it,
相反 却是欧文夫妇买下了
but no, it's Mr and Mrs Owen.
你见过他们吗?
You've met them?
没有 只有信件来往
No, everything by letter.
一座岛?
An island?
在海边?
By the sea?
海岛一般都在海边
Islands are generally by the sea.
麻烦你把那盒子递给我 奥德丽
The box, if you please, Audrey.
呃... 我... 我不知道... 也许我不合适...
Erm... I... I don't... Maybe I'm not suited...
你就是她想要的
You are who she wants.
而且工资不菲
And it's very well-paid.
如果你符合要求 这就是一份长期工作
There's a permanent position on offer, if you fit the bill.
- 好的 但是...  - 这是预付工资
- Yes, but...  - For immediate expenses.
亲爱的布伦特小姐 我十分敬仰您
很期待见到您
亲爱的阿姆斯特朗医生
女性精神科专家
劳伦斯·约翰·沃格雷夫 普林斯顿广场 伦敦
亲爱的安东尼
来我位于士兵岛的避暑山庄一聚
亲爱的布洛尔探长
我需要一个目光犀利的人
菲利普·隆巴德
局面动荡不安
亲爱的麦克阿瑟将军
军事历史学家
您诚挚的 U·N·欧文
这是... 话剧用的?
And... and this is for a play?
要在伦敦西区演的?
In the West End?
我会被署名进创作团队吧?
And will I be credited in the programme?
女士们 先生们!
Ladies and gentlemen!
请肃静!
Silence, please!
你们被指控犯有以下罪名
You are charged with the following indictments.
天啊! 该死!
Oh, my God! Bloody hell!
去死吧 混蛋!
Damn you, you stupid bastard!
剩下的也来了...
Oh, well. Here are the others...
我是克莱索恩
I'm Miss Claythorne.
欧文太太的秘书
Mrs Owen's secretary.
您是纳拉科特先生吗?
Are you Mr Narracott?
除了我没人会拿这个标志 已经接了两位客人过去
Ain't no-one else holding the sign. Already taken two over.
一个挑三拣四的老太太 一个神采奕奕的小伙子
Fussy old maid and some flashy young lad.
我就像小提琴师的手肘一样不停进出这个海港
Been in and out of this harbour like a fiddler's elbow.
海夫自有套路
Sea dogs have their own etiquette.
各位下午好
Well, good afternoon.
麦克阿瑟将军
General Macarthur.
天啊! 见到你真是无上荣幸
Good Lord! What an honour to meet you.
- 我是沃格雷夫  - 沃格雷夫法官?
- Wargrave.  - Justice Wargrave?
我也无比荣幸 先生
The honour's all mine, sir.
我已经退休了
Retired from justice now.
您是...?
Mr...?
我叫菲利普·隆巴德
Lombard. Philip.
您呢 先生?
And you, sir?
我叫戴维斯
Davis.
你们还走不走了?
Are you coming, or not?
那么... 我们走吧?
Well... shall we?
这边走 就在这...
This way, just up here...
午安!
Good afternoon!
欢迎来到士兵岛
Welcome to Soldier Island.
好了 跟我来
Right. Come along.
抱歉 有什么问题吗?
Sorry, is there a problem?
我收费多少就送多少路 先生
Well, that's as far as my fee will take me, sir.
天啊...
Oh, for God's sake...
呃... 戴维斯?
Er... Davis?
戴维斯?
Davis?
万分乐意...
I'd be grateful...
当然
Of course.
那么 罗杰斯...
Well, Rogers...
这里的主人... 什么时候可以见到他们?
Our hosts... when can we expect to meet them?
今晚人应该就会到齐了 先生
We should be a full house by tonight, sir.
下午好
Ah, afternoon.
我是安东尼·马斯顿
Tony Marston.
很期待在晚餐见到你们
Well, I look forward to meeting you all at dinner.
送一杯琴汤尼到我房间
A stiff G&T in my room.
是 先生
Sir.
欧文太太有没有给我留指示?
Did Mrs Owen leave any instructions for me?
- 我是她的秘书  - 她只关照要确保您居住舒适
- I'm the secretary.  - Only to ensure that you were comfortable
并且一切如您所愿就好 克莱索恩小姐
and had everything you wished for, Miss Claythorne.
男士们都请随我而来
Now, if the gentlemen would follow me,
罗杰斯太太会给那位小姐领路
Mrs Rogers will escort the lady.
谢谢你 戴维斯...
Well, thank you, Davis...
我的朋友有没有... 卡尔明顿太太... 康斯坦斯·卡尔明顿太太...
Did my friend, Mrs Culmington... Mrs Constance Culmington...
她有没有改计划 你知道吗?
did she change her plans, do you know?
不 恐怕我不知道
No, I'm afraid I don't.
哼! 这事真是怪异
Mmm! Ridiculously vague.
抱歉 我刚拿到这份工作
Well, I'm sorry. I only just recently got the job.
不不不 不是说你 克莱索恩小姐
No, no, no, no. Not you, Miss Claythorne.
我说的是整场安排
I mean, this whole arrangement.
欧文夫妇邀请我来这见我的朋友 而她却不在这里
The Owens invited me here to meet my friend and she's not even here.
非常奇怪 真是奇怪得很
Very strange. Very strange indeed.
- 需要帮忙吗? 我扶你  - 你太好了
- Can I help you? Here.  - Oh, too kind.
十个士兵小男孩 为了吃饭去奔走
噎死一个没法救 十个只剩九
别来烦我
Leave me alone.
看看你这样子
Look at the state of you.
我要去给牛肉抹油了
I've got to baste my beef.
还有我的蛋奶酥 托马斯 我的蛋奶酥怎么办?
And my souffles, Thomas, what about my souffle?
我又不能给她更衣 对吧?
Well, I can't dress her, can I?
快去
Go on.
是童年阴影吗?
Was it a childhood affliction?
你的眼睛?
Your eyes?
不是的 夫人
No, madam.
突然出现的症状
Came on all suddenly.
受到惊吓? 生活巨变?
Oh... Shock, maybe? Sudden change?
对不起 夫人 我不知道
Begging your pardon, madam, I don't know.
你一定知道
You must know.
对不起 夫人 我不知道
Begging your pardon, madam, I don't.
我一直认为 会轻易
I always think it's rather a weakness,
受周围环境影响 是一种懦弱
to be so affected by something in one's circumstances.
要不就是放纵 徒劳无功
Rather indulgent, almost vain.
我们要坚强 罗杰斯太太 尤其是这种时期
We must be strong, Mrs Rogers, especially in these times.
要勇敢...
We must be valiant...
也要秉持道德
and virtuous.
我们要做英国女人
And we must be Englishwomen.
好的 夫人
Yes, madam.
给你一点建议...
And a little advice...
以后 上楼服侍女士们之前...
in future, a splash of Eau de Cologne...
喷一点古龙香水
before you come upstairs to attend on the ladies.
我自然明白在厨房工作的艰辛不易
I appreciate it's hot, working in the kitchen,
但无需如此明显地表现出来
but there's no need to announce it quite so emphatically.
对不起 夫人
Beg your pardon, madam.
罐头食品
Tinned goods.
部队 战争 战争
Troops. War. The war.
罐头食品
Tinned goods.
沃格雷夫法官 拙劣的自我介绍让你见笑了
Judge Wargrave, I'm terribly sorry for the clumsy introduction.
我不太习惯旅行 完全失了该有的风度
I'm a terrible traveller, completely lose my bearings.
我们没迟到吧?
Are we on time?
正好赶上
Only just.
先生
Ah, sir.
您这么快就准备妥当了呀
You're ready sooner than we'd anticipated.
- 楼上是什么?  - 只是阁楼 先生
- What's up there?  - Just roof space, sir.
先生... 主人和我说过
Ah, sir... I've been advised
楼上的地板不是很牢固
that the footing isn't particularly sturdy up there.
最好不要上去 以免害您一不小心
Best avoided, lest you make an unexpected entrance
进了别人的卧室 先生...
into one of the bedrooms, sir...
还是从天花板掉进去的
by way of the ceiling.
我领您去休息室吧 先生?
May I show you to the drawing room, sir?
在等待其他宾客时给您来杯餐前酒如何?
Perhaps an aperitif, whilst you await the other guests?
戴维斯先生
Ah... Mr Davis.
看起来你需要喝一杯啊
You look like a man who could use a drink.
真是不谋而合 一小杯即可
Hmm! How very congenial. Perhaps a small... snifter.
罗杰斯先生 请带路
Mr Rogers, lead the way.
小姐?
Miss?
您在找什么吗 小姐?
Is there something you're looking for, Miss?
这里是地下室 小姐
Because this is the belowstairs, Miss.
只有工作人员可进
For staff.
我就是工作人员
Well, I am staff.
小姐 我们有非常严格的规定
Miss, we had very strict instructions
要将你当作宾客招待
that you were to be treated as a guest.
宾客不能到楼下来
Guests don't come below stairs.
但是听起来好像你是在赶我走
It rather sounds as though you're asking me to leave.
欧文夫妇还邀请了多少人?
How many more are you expecting, with the Owens?
等他们都到了就知道了
We shall know when they arrive.
那只有你们两个人 怎么应付得来?
And how will you cope, just the two of you?
罗杰斯和我很能干
Rogers and myself is competent.
足够能干了
More than.
那可以请您上楼了吗?
So, if you please?
干得漂亮 姑娘
Well done, girl.
多么悠然的晚上啊
What an idyllic evening.
看这苍穹!
The sky!
怎么会有人不相信这是造物主的杰作?
How can one not believe in a creator?
我是戴维斯
Davis.
我是埃米莉·布伦特
Emily Brett.
爱德华·阿姆斯特朗
Edward Armstrong.
我的房间里也有一个
There's one in my room, too.
我猜每个房间都有一个
I imagine there's one in every room.
这是士兵岛嘛 不奇怪
Well... Soldier Island. It makes sense.
挺有趣的
It's amusing.
我强烈怀疑这里的主人擅长幻想
I have a strong suspicion our hosts are inclined to whimsy.
我不能评论我们的主人
I cannot comment on our hosts.
多好的小秘书
Good little secretary.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我们相识的方式不太对 是吧?
We've got off on the wrong foot, haven't we?
但是你确实有双美腿
But you do have very pretty legs.
- 不欣赏可就太暴殄天物了  - 隆巴德先生...
- It would have been remiss not to admire them.  - Mr Lombard...
你似乎已经认定了我是某种样子的女人
you seem to be under the impression that I am a particular kind of woman.
但我保证 我绝不是
And I assure you that I am not.
我不喜欢被人盯着看
I do not like to be looked at.
我看人的直觉很准
I get instincts about people.
我对你就有种直觉
I've an instinct about you.
我觉得你在伪装
I think you're pretending.
要喝酒吗 马斯顿先生?
A drink, Mr Marston?
苦味杜松子酒 粉如处子的脸颊
Pink gin. Pink as a virgin's blush.
- 我不知道你的名字  - 菲利普·隆巴德
- Didn't catch your name.  - Philip Lombard.
爱尔兰人 你一定认识克莱索恩一家
Irish. You must know the Corkerons.
我的好朋友
Great chums of mine.
无比与人为善
Endlessly simpatico.
有点名气的人都知道他们
Anyone who's anyone knows them.
你爱打赌吗 隆巴德?
Are you a betting man, Lombard?
看情况
It depends.
今天晚上某个时刻
At some point this evening,
那些老不死的家伙中的一个总会谈论起战争
one of those crumbling old roaks will start talking about the war.
然后他会来问你是否遗憾自己错过了上一场战争
And then he'll ask us both if we aren't damned sorry to have missed the last one
下一场战争又该如何共同合作 尽责报国
and how we should be gung ho to do our duty in the next.
但不会有下一场战争的
Not that there's going to be a next one.
总是会有下一场战争
There's always a next one.
那你怎么说? 赌吗?
So, how about it? A bet?
赢的可能性太小了
The odds are too short.
听听他们 喋喋不休地讨论着过往
Listen to them. Clinging on.
他们还觉得自己很了不起
They think they still mean something
但哪怕他们死了 也绝不会有人发现或在乎...
but nobody at all would notice, or care, if they just...
我会对他们释放无比魅力的
I'm going to be exceptionally charming to them.
好吧 克莱索恩小姐
Oh, all right, Miss Claythorne.
抱歉 我不该盯着你看 这下你该开心点了吧
If it'll make you happy, I'm sorry for staring.
隆巴德先生
Mr Lombard,
我觉得你从不会对任何事感到抱歉
I doubt you're ever sorry for anything.
聪明姑娘
Smart girl.
女士们先生们 龙虾蛋奶酥
Ladies and gentlemen, lobster souffle.
但愿不要太油腻
I hope it isn't too rich.
我在家吃饭都很清淡
I always dine so modestly at home.
我不用 谢谢
I won't, thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们以前见过 是吗?
We've met before, you know?
抱歉 我的记忆力已经大不如前了
Oh, forgive me, my memory is not what it was.
也许你以前给过我证据?
Perhaps you gave evidence before me?
不 如果是这样 我会记得的
No, no, it wasn't that, I'd remember that.
一定是别的事...
It's something else...
我会记起来的
It'll come to me.
我看不明白这些东西
I'm not at all sure about these.
这东西看起来很... 怪异
They look very... pagan.
它们是十个小士兵 那首诗歌里提到的
They're the ten little soldiers. You know, from the poem.
我能背得出那诗
Hmm. I know it off by heart.
我小的时候 我奶奶背给我听过
When I was a little boy, my nanny used to recite it to me.
我觉得她是用这首诗来吓我 想让我乖一点
I imagine she wanted to terrify me into being good.
起作用了吗?
Did it work?
当然 我一直都很一丝不苟
Well, I've always been a stickler, yes.
对规章制度一丝不苟
Stickler for the rules.
可能我是个迟钝的孩子吧!
I was probably a rather dull boy!
这我可想象不出来 将军
I really can't imagine that, General.
不过 你不该称它为诗歌 克莱索恩小姐
Although, you shouldn't call it a poem, Miss Claythorne.
它算是打油诗
It's doggerel.
诗歌应当令人振奋
Poetry should be uplifting.
我同意你的观点 布伦特小姐
I agree with you, Miss Brent.
看看第一印象错得有多离谱
Well, that shows how wrong first impressions are.
我认为你不是那种会欣赏诗歌的男子
I didn't think you were the type of gentleman to appreciate poetry.
戴维斯先生意外的很有深度
Mr Davis has hidden depths.
蛋奶酥很好吃
The souffle is delicious.
口感很轻盈
Mmm, very light.
在40多年的刑法执法生涯中 我面对过
In over 40 years in criminal law, I have come face to face
最堕落邪恶的人类 却心无恐惧
with the most depraved examples of mankind and felt no fear.
但看到年轻小姐挥舞着曲棍
But I quail in terror, Miss Claythorne,
克莱索恩小姐 我心里怕极了
at the thought of young ladies brandishing hockey sticks.
她们没那么坏 法官先生 只是有时有点兴奋过头 有些吵闹
They're not so bad, Judge. A little over-excited and noisy, sometimes.
真是年轻人的特点
Oh, the prerogative of youth.
我确信你可以为她们树个好榜样
And I'm sure you set them a very fine example.
有时你会害怕他们会端上来什么糟糕的菜品
Sometimes, you dread what filth they're going to serve,
- 但这菜还挺不错的  - 欧文夫妇是非常慷慨的主人
- but this is actually very decent.  - The Owens are always generous hosts.
他们是你的朋友吗 戴维斯先生?
Friends of yours, Mr Davis?
是生意伙伴
Business acquaintances.
我做罐头生意
I'm in tinned goods.
给军队提供炖菜起的家
The firm started off supplying troops with stew.
罐头食品帮我们赢得了战争
Tinned goods is what helped us win the war.
我猜... 吃饱饭才能打胜仗
Well, I suppose... I suppose an army marches on its stomach.
开始了...
Here we go...
天啊 我记得那炖菜
God, I remember that stew.
我猜是皇家军队医疗队吧 阿姆斯特朗医生?
RAMC, I presume, Dr Armstrong?
没错
That's right.
在比利时和法国的伤员运输站和医院工作
Clearing stations and then hospitals in Belgium and France.
也许你也被采访过了吧
Perhaps you're being interviewed as well.
什么采访 将军?
Interviewed, General?
欧文先生虽不是军人 却是个博学多识的军事历史学家
Yes, Mr Owen is an amateur, but very knowledgeable military historian.
他在写有关法国
He's writing about France,
- 1917年时前线决定性决策的书  - 天啊 终于结束了
- about the decisive actions on the Front in 1917.  - Oh, for God's sake, it's over.
没有 我... 来这里就是为了逃开那些的
No, I'm, er... I'm just here to get away from it all.
欧文先生是个有趣的男人... 名字也很有趣
Interesting man, Mr Owen... and an interesting name.
尤利克·诺尔曼
Ulick Norman.
真奇怪 欧文太太的名字是尤纳·南希...
How funny. Mrs Owen is Una Nancy...
首字母一样
Matching initials.
我得承认 我对"尤利克"这名字有点忧虑
Must confess, I was a little worried about the "Ulick".
现下的形势下 这看起来有点像... 日耳曼人的名字
Given the current climate, it might be seen as somewhat... Teutonic.
他可是最爱国的人
You couldn't hope to meet a more patriotic man.
况且还能有什么名字比"诺曼"更像英国人呢?
And what could be more English than "Norman"?
太神奇了!
Oh, it's magical!
罗杰斯太太很有天赋
Mrs Rogers has the gift.
她也许看上去像僵尸 但菜做得很不错
She might look like the undead, but she can definitely cook.
欧文夫妇什么时候到?
When might we expect the Owens?
他们没打来电话吗?
Have they not telephoned?
这岛上没有电话 夫人
There's no telephone on the island, Madam.
纳拉科特先生每天早上
Mr Narracott brings messages,
送邮件和食材来的时候 会带信来
along with the post and kitchen supplies every morning.
我想明天他就会带着欧文夫妇的电报
I imagine tomorrow, he will either bring a telegram from the Owens,
或他们本人过来
or they will accompany him.
对了 罗杰斯 给那个纳拉科特几先令
Ah-ah, Rogers, give that Narracott chap a couple of bob,
让他替我看下车
ask him to watch my car.
车就停在港口
It's parked up by the harbour.
延森牌的
The Jensen.
当然可以 先生
Of course, sir.
我也会向罗杰斯太太转告您的赞美
I shall pass on your compliments to Mrs Rogers.
听我说 戴维斯 欧文夫妇...
Look here, Davis. The Owens...
他们是喜爱热闹的人吗?
Are they fun-loving types?
"喜爱热闹"?
"Fun-loving"?
没错 因为这里有些事不对劲
Yeah, cos there's something a tad off here.
听着 我收到了一封信 邀请我参加派对
Now, I had a letter inviting me to a house party.
是年轻人会玩的 懂吗? 香槟 音乐...
Pretty young things, you know? Champagne, music...
但除了这位似乎可以在开心些的隆巴德
And apart from Lombard, who looks like he could cut up a bit lively,
你们其他人似乎都不是喜欢热闹派对的人
the rest of you don't really look like fun-loving house party types.
我无疑冒犯
No offence.
那延森牌的车是你的?
Your car, the Jensen?
你看到了? 她是不是很美?
Oh, you saw her? Isn't she a beauty?
说实话 我无法想象我会爱一个人
I honestly can't imagine loving a person
甚于崇拜爱戴延森车
as much as I worship and adore the Jensen.
你把我逼下了路
You ran me off the road.
我没有
No, I didn't.
你把我逼下了路
You ran me off the road.
什么时候?
When?
我当时正自顾自好好开车 结果你超我车...
I was driving along, minding my own business, when you overtook me...
天知道你开得有多块... 然后就把我逼下了路
going God knows how fast... and you ran me off the road.
我看到有人以可悲的龟爬速度...
Well, I saw someone going at a pitiful speed...
好了 听着 马斯顿...
Now, look here, Marston...
我觉得眼下这情形 你道个歉再握个手
I think an apology and a handshake between gentlemen
是最好不过的了
would be just the thing here.
- 但我并没有做错事!  - 你把我逼下了路!
- But I haven't done anything wrong!  - You ran me off the road!
我也许是超了你的车 但我姨妈开车都比你带劲
I might have over-taken you, but my great aunt drives with more zip.
如果你没法控制自己的车
And if you can't control your car,
- 那就真的不应该开车了...  - 你个小混蛋!
- then you really shouldn't be behind the wheel...  - You little shit!
你把我逼下了路
You ran me off the road
竟然还有脸跟我说那是我的错?!
and then you have the temerity to tell me it's my fault?!
冷静点 老小子 你脸都有点红了
Careful, old boy. Getting a little red in the face there.
拜托了 二位! 还有女士在场呢
Gentleman, please! There are ladies present.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这周太辛苦了
It's been a long week.
你说得对 将军
You're right, General.
应该绅士间握个手
A handshake between gentlemen.
快点 阿姆斯特朗 来握一下
Come on, Armstrong. Put it there.
我们做朋友吧
Let's be pals.
快到时间了
Nearly there.
干得不错
Good work, eh?
罗杰斯 我没烟了
Rogers, I'm out of cigarettes.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
你参加过那些战役 将军?
So, what battles were you involved with, General?
我在西北边境服过役
Well, I served on the North West frontier,
还有南非和法国
in South Africa, and of course, in France.
- 赢过吗?  - 我讨厌这个习俗...
- Win any?  - I loathe this convention...
留男人在那里抽烟聊天
leaving men to their cigars and their "stories".
恰是习俗 克莱索恩小姐
Convention, Miss Claythorne,
使我们在迫在眉睫的混乱前保持团结
is what keeps us together in the face of impending chaos.
到时间了吗?
Is it time?
你先端过去
You start serving.
不 不 我来倒咖啡
No, no. No, I'll pour the coffee.
你厨房那儿一定很忙
You must be very busy in the kitchen.
多谢小姐
Miss.
晚餐很不错 罗杰斯太太
Excellent dinner, Mrs Rogers.
欧文夫妇能请到你真是幸运
The Owens are lucky to have you.
我一定会告诉他们的
I'll certainly be telling them so.
谢谢您 夫人
Thank you, Madam.
你上班的学校在哪儿?
Whereabouts is your school?
我想您应该没听说过 那学校并不出名
I doubt you'd have heard of it. It's not particularly well-known.
也不怎么出色
Nor particularly good, either.
您为什么这么说?
Why do you say that?
不然 你也就不会在夏天出来找工作了
Otherwise, you would not be needing employment in the summer months.
他们的学费不够高 付的工资也就不够高
Their fees are not high enough, nor is their pay.
倒不是我不赞同你找工作充实时光...
Not that I disapprove of you seeking employment and being busy...
我很赞同
far from it.
但为什么要在个三流学校
But why teach in a third-rate establishment,
教三流的女学生呢?
producing third-rate girls?
我觉得她们不值得你花时间和精力上去
Barely worth your time and attention, I would have thought.
女士们 先生们!
Ladies and gentlemen!
请肃静!
Silence, please!
是谁在说话?
Who is that?
你们被指控犯有以下罪名
You are charged with the following indictments.
爱德华·乔治·阿姆斯特朗 你谋杀了路易莎·玛丽·克利斯...
Edward George Armstrong, that you murdered Louisa Mary Clees...
- 这是谁?  - 我不知道 先生...
- Who is this?  - I don't know, sir...
埃米莉·卡罗琳·布伦特 你谋杀了比阿特丽斯·泰勒...
Emily Caroline Brent, that you murdered Beatrice Taylor...
- 这是谁?  - 这是什么意思?
- Who is this?  - What's the meaning of this?
威廉·亨利·布洛尔 你谋杀了詹姆斯·斯蒂芬·兰道...
William Henry Blore, that you did murder James Stephen Landor...
上帝啊!
God almighty!
维拉·伊丽莎白·克莱索恩
Vera Elizabeth Claythorne,
你谋杀了西里尔·奥格尔维·汉密尔顿
that you did murder Cyril Ogilvie Hamilton.
菲利普·隆巴德 你谋杀了21名
Philip Lombard, that you did murder 21 men,
东非部落的土著人
members of an East African tribe.
约翰·戈登·麦克阿瑟 你谋杀了亨利·里奇蒙...
John Gordon MacArthur, that you did murder Henry Richmond...
这声音是从哪儿来的?
Where is this coming from?
- 安东尼·詹姆斯·马斯顿 你谋杀了约翰和露西·库姆斯...  - 我们走 罗杰斯
- Anthony James Marston, that you did murder John and Lucy Coombes...  - Let's go, Rogers.
我从没听到过这个
I never heard of them.
劳伦斯·约翰·沃格雷夫
Lawrence John Wargrave,
你谋杀了爱德华·塞顿
that you did murder Edward Seton.
让开
Get out of my way.
托马斯和埃塞尔·罗杰斯...
Thomas and Ethel Rogers...
你们谋杀了詹尼弗·布雷迪
that you did murder Jennifer Brady.
- 托马斯?  - 狱中的罪犯们...
- Thomas?  - Prisoners at the bar...
你们是否认罪?
how do you plead?
哦... 罗杰斯太太?
Oh... Mrs Rogers?
- 她只是晕过去了  - 我去拿我的包
- She just took a turn.  - I'll go fetch my bag.
- 她会没事的  - 这事我说了算
- She'll be all right.  - I'll be the judge of that.
- 唱片?  - 还叫告别演出
- A record?  - It's called Swan Song.
他们到底在玩什么?
What the hell are they playing at?
嗯? 他们到底在玩什么?
Huh? What the hell are they playing at?
- 放开我!  - 该死的欧文夫妇 他们想玩什么?
- Get off me!  - The damn Owens, what's their game?
放开他 马斯顿 他根本不认识他们 他不是戴维斯
Put him down, Marston, he doesn't know them. He's not Davis.
我叫布洛尔
I'm Blore.
威廉·布洛尔探长
Detective Sergeant William Blore.
你怎么知道的?
How did you know?
直觉
Instinct.
我去喝杯酒
I need a drink.
真是的! 这些荒诞的虚假指控!
Really! These grotesque, false accusations!
正是 将军!
Indeed, General!
我们应该等医生和罗杰斯过来
We should wait for the doctor and Rogers.
我们应该等大家都到场
We should wait until everyone is together.
说得好 探长 我们都听警察的话吧
Well said, Tubs. Let's all listen to the policeman.
克莱索恩小姐?
Miss Claythorne?
给
Here.
这药很温和 但能助眠
It's mild, but it will help you sleep.
罗杰斯 我猜有些关于这里主人的问题
I suspect, Rogers, that there are questions about our hosts
只有你能回答
that only you can answer.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
那给你几分钟 宽慰下你的妻子
A few minutes, then, to settle your wife.
多谢先生
Sir.
我早就说了!
I told you!
我早就说了...
I told you...
镇静下来 女人!
Pull yourself together, woman!
别想着耍花样 迟钝的婊子
Stop flapping your trap, you dozy bitch.
谢谢
Thank you.
罗杰斯马上过来
Rogers is coming.
罗杰斯
Well, Rogers?
看... "根据我的指示...
See... "On my instructions...
在特定的时间播放唱片"
Put the record on at such a time".
他们说这是个惊喜 是个派对的游戏
We were told it was to be a surprise, a party game.
- 派对游戏!  - 但你当时和我们在一起
- Some party game!  - But you were in the room with us.
唱片有延迟效果
There's a delay on the record.
有人为此花了很多时间和功夫
Somebody went to a lot of time and expense.
如果我知道唱片里的内容
If I'd known what was on the record,
就绝不会参与这件事
I'd never have been a part of it.
里面对我和罗杰斯太太的指控? 绝不属实!
What is said about me and Mrs Rogers? Never!
所以根本不是真的?
Nothing in it, then?
布雷迪小姐就像我们的家人
Miss Brady were like family to us.
我们为她尽心尽力
We did everything for her.
她身体不好 非常虚弱
She weren't well. Frail as a bird.
但她在账户里给我们留了一小笔遗产...
But on account of how she left us a small legacy...
某些人就开始对此口不择言了
Well, some folk will say anything to hurt.
恐怕我得说家庭服务的圈子里嫉妒横生
There's a lot of jealousy amongst domestic service, I'm afraid to say.
地下室里就是一窝阴险狡诈的人
Below stairs is very often a nest of vipers.
谢谢你 罗杰斯 如果我们有需要会打电话给你
Thank you, Rogers. We'll ring if we require anything further.
我经常会遇到懒惰且怀恨在心的仆人
I've had more than my fair share of lazy and vindictive staff.
- 我相信罗杰斯  - 但这说不通啊
- I believe Rogers.  - Doesn't make any sense.
我根本没见过什么约翰和露西·库姆斯
I've never even met a John and Lucy Coombes.
真是充满恶意的荒唐话
Malicious nonsense.
路易莎·克利斯是个来做手术的病人
Louise Clees was a surgical patient.
手术很复杂 有危险性 大家都明白的
It was risky, there were complications. Everyone knew that.
但真等出事的时候 大家都会把错怪到医生身上
But the moment anything goes wrong, it's "blame the bloody surgeon".
没人责怪你 医生
No-one's blaming you, Doctor.
但某人在责怪我!
Well, someone is!
亨利·里奇蒙是我手下最棒的年轻警官之一
Henry Richmond was one of my finest young officers,
在为国家履行神圣使命的时候壮烈牺牲
who fell in the pursuit of his gallant duty for King and Country.
竟有人听信这些卑鄙的谣言 真是可恶...
It is repugnant that these vile rumours should be given credence...
可恶至极!
Repugnant!
爱德华·塞顿有罪
Edward Seton was guilty.
我认可了一些不能纳入呈堂证供的证据
I was party to evidence that was not admissible before the court.
但他的确有罪
But he was guilty.
我唯一碰到兰道的时候 就是给他上手铐的时候
The only time I laid hands on Landor was to put handcuffs on him.
他是个堕落的酒鬼
He was a degenerate and a drunk.
被自己的呕吐物噎死了
He choked on his own puke.
西里尔... 那个小男孩...
Cyril... The little boy...
我是他的保姆
I was his governess.
他不应该去游泳的 他还不够强壮
He wasn't supposed to swim, he wasn't strong.
但他溜了出去 我...
But he sneaked off and I...
我也不是很擅长游泳
I wasn't a good enough swimmer.
我就是不够优秀
I just wasn't good enough.
我试了
I tried.
我真的试过想救他
I really tried to save him.
他可怜的母亲崩溃了 彻底崩溃了
His poor mother was broken, she was so broken.
我... 也是被别人救上来的
I... I had to be rescued.
我差点淹死
I almost drowned.
什么人会这样说话呢?
Who could say something like this?
某种恶意的玩笑
Some sort of vicious joke.
如果你们觉得这很幽默
Well, if that's your sense of humour,
那你们的脑子一定有些问题
there's something wrong with your wiring.
滑稽剧时间到了
Time for the funny farm.
我那指控倒完全属实
It was pinpoint accurate about me.
21个人?
21 men?
我就知道有人会瞎说
I always thought someone would blab.
真是神奇 某些人安安稳稳地
It's amazing how people get an attack of conscience
躺自家床上睡觉 竟会突然良心发现
when they're safely tucked away in their beds.
你这个可怕的男人!
You terrible man!
真是个可怕至极的男人!
You terrible, terrible man!
就是你这样的人...
It's people like you...
你这样的男人...
men like you...
害我们的传教士身陷险境!
that put our missionaries in such danger!
你们的传教士 带着上帝和梅毒!
Oh, your missionaries, with their God and their syphilis!
我可不是唯一在非洲杀了人的白人 布伦特小姐
I am not the only white killer in Africa, Miss Brent.
隆巴德先生 你是个该死的侩子手!
Lombard, you, sir, are a bloody butcher!
我也对此供认不讳
And I'm holding my hands up to it.
所以 要么就是我为了吓吓各位编了这个故事
So, either I'm embellishing a story for shocking effect,
要么这房间里都是骗子 我是唯一说了实话的人
or I'm the only one telling the truth in a room full of liars.
- 你怎么敢!  - 收回那句话 先生!
- How dare you!  - Take that back, sir!
请别说了 女士们先生们 别说了!
Enough, please, ladies and gentlemen. Enough!
这有什么好处呢?
What good can it do?
我认为我们应该回房休息
My feeling is that we should retire
准备好明天和纳拉科特先生一起离开
and be ready to leave tomorrow with Mr Narracott.
如果欧文夫妇和他一起来了呢?
What if the Owens are with him?
我们当面对质 但依旧要离开
We confront them, but we leave.
哪怕隆巴德先生供认了可怕的罪行...
And despite Mr Lombard's devastating confession...
我们都是这出残忍骗局的受害者
we are all victims of a cruel hoax.
我们不应再多争论 夸大这些控诉
We shouldn't dignify these accusations with any more debate.
同意吗?
Agreed?
- 当然  - 附议
- Certainly.  - Hear, hear.
约翰和露西·库姆斯... 一定是那两个孩子
John and Lucy Coombes... they must have been those two kids.
我是说看在上帝的份上 哪种父母会让孩子晚上在外面玩?
I mean, what sort of parents let kids play out in the dark, for God's sake?
这太不负责任了
It's completely irresponsible.
我为此被吊销驾照六个月 真是个麻烦事
I lost my license for six months. It was a terrific nuisance.
噢 原来你当时在开车呀 真让人意外!
Oh, you were driving, were you? What a surprise!
那完全是运气不好 仅此而已
It was jolly bad luck, that's all.
我根本躲不过的
No, I didn't stand a chance.
那俩可怜的孩子...
Those poor children...
你就是个该死的疯子 马斯顿!
You're a bloody maniac, Marston!
我根本就没开多快
I wasn't even driving that fast.
你在英格兰不能开那么快
You can't, not in England.
但欧洲大陆就不一样了 我是说他们理解飙车的真谛
It's not like the Continent. I mean, they understand motoring over there.
无论你们怎么评价德国佬都好 但他们的路棒极了
Say what you like about the Krauts, but their roads are magnificent.
延森车爱死那路了
The Jensen loves them.
我完全可以放开速度 随她奔驰
I can really open her up and let her rip.
- 没事吧?  - 他噎住了!
- All right?  - He's choking!
他吐血了!
He's bleeding!
- 让他躺地上!  - 把他扶开!
- Get him down!  - Get him off me!
他死了
He's dead.
天上的父啊 请看顾这身陷痛苦的灵魂 保护我们...
Heavenly father, watch over this soul in torment and protect us...
阿姆斯特朗
Armstrong.
过来
Come here.
好吧 处于对他家人的尊重
Well, perhaps we ought to get rid of the stimulant,
也许我们应该扔了这些兴奋剂
out of respect to the family.
可不想惹上丑闻啊
Don't want to cause a scandal.
这事归警察管了 医生
It's a police matter now, Doctor.
无论身份是否尊贵 规矩都是一样的
Same set of rules, if you're posh or not.
那好吧
Very well.
我们死定了 托马斯
We're damned, Thomas.
死定了
We're damned.
我们要下地狱了!
We're going to hell!
谁?
Yes?
是谁?
Who is it?
医生 求你了!
Doctor, please!
别碰我
Don't touch me.
我知道自己在干什么
I know what I'm doing.
阿姆斯特朗医生?
Dr Armstrong?
嗯 什么事?
Yes? What is it?
您能跟我来一下吗?
Can you come, please?
她已经死了几个小时了
She's been dead for some hours.
我...
I'll, er...
鉴于现在的情况 我去通知其他人别对早餐
I'll inform the others not to expect too much in the way of breakfast,
抱太大期望了
given the circumstances.
不用 先生
No, sir.
我们会提供全套早餐的
Full breakfast will be provided.
你很敬业
Good man.
最好别细想 保持忙碌
Best not to dwell. Keep busy.
阿姆斯特朗医生
Dr Armstrong.
我听到你起床了
I heard you get up.
罗杰斯太太的情况恶化了吗?
Has Mrs Rogers got worse?
算是吧 她死了
Somewhat. She's dead.
- 死了?  - 在睡梦里死掉的
- Dead?  - Died in her sleep.
她去得很平和 不用太过担心
It was quite peaceful. Nothing to be alarmed about.
等等
Wait.
等等 我...
Wait, I, er...
我下来等你的时候看到了这个 请跟我来
I came down here to wait for you and I saw this. Please.
现在才来告别吻太晚了吧 探长
Bit late for the kiss of life, Tubs.
你真是个聪明鬼
Smart arse, you are.
你自己闻闻
Have a sniff yourself.
- 本来有十个瓷像  - 和童谣里说的一样 没错
- There were ten of them.  - From the nursery rhyme, the poem? Yes.
对 请你数一下 阿姆斯特朗医生
Yes. Count them for me, please, Dr Armstrong.
现在是八个 对吧?
There are eight, aren't there?
八个瓷像 象征着这里的八个人
Eight figures for the eight people here.
告诉我 我没数错
Tell me I'm right.
请告诉我 我没数错!
Please tell me I'm right!
我想这事一定有个非常合理的解释
I'm sure there is a perfectly rational explanation for this.
杏仁味
Almonds.
才不是什么杏仁味
Almonds be buggered.
是氰化物
Cyanide.
我相信你不会对着我们歇斯底里吧 克莱索恩小姐
I trust you're not going to unravel on us, Miss Claythorne.
疯女人太无聊了
Hysterical women are so boring.
谢谢你去救他 谢谢你尽力了 谢谢你 谢谢你
Thank you for trying, thank you for trying, thank you, thank you,
谢谢你尽力了 天啊 天啊 天啊...
thank you for trying, oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, God...
我想游到礁石那边去!
I want to swim to the rocks!
西里尔亲爱的 你知道不行 你还不够强壮
Cyril, darling, you know you can't. You're not strong enough.
- 够强壮了!  - 西里尔 听话
- I am!  - Cyril, behave yourself.
听克莱索恩小姐的话 亲爱的
Listen to Miss Claythorne, dearest.
不要!
No!
这真是太调皮了! 真是抱歉 克莱索恩小姐
That's incredibly naughty! I'm so sorry, Miss Claythorne.
天啊 他怎么就那么激动
Oh, dear. He's getting all worked up.
西里尔 你会害自己生病的
Cyril, you'll make yourself ill.
这是怎么了?
What's all this, now?
雨果叔叔!
Uncle Hugo!
我大老远就能听到你在叫 你这个小淘气
I can hear you shouting from miles away, you young rascal.
感谢上帝... 你来得正是时候
Oh, thank heavens... in the nick of time.
奥利维亚 你和往常一样光彩四射
Olivia, you look absolutely radiant, as ever.
空洞的奉承话 我都晒红了 样子可笑极了
Empty flattery. I'm completely raddled and utterly hideous.
我想我还不认识这位小姐
I don't believe I've had the pleasure.
雨果 这位是克莱索恩小姐
Hugo, this is Miss Claythorne,
她在学校经常帮忙照顾西里尔
who was doing so much to help Cyril in the schoolroom.
你去踏浪了吗 将军?
Have you been for a paddle, General?
你是什么人 隆巴德?
What are you, Lombard?
雇佣兵?
A mercenary?
杀手?
Gun for hire?
士兵?
A soldier?
你并不隶属于我所知的任何军队 但仍是某种士兵
Not from any army I'd recognise, but still, a soldier of sorts.
你不必担心我是什么人
You don't need to worry about what I am.
总有那么一瞬间 对吧?
There's always a moment, isn't there?
在袭击 进攻 轰炸和混乱前...
Before the attack, the advance, the bombardment, the chaos...
总有一瞬间的死寂
a moment of absolute calm.
听着...
Listen...
现在是不是很像那个瞬间?
doesn't this feel like that moment?
我从不是个寻求安稳的人 将军
I was never a man for calm, General.
我们从这里看不到港口
We can't see the harbour from here.
也就意味着他们看不见我们
Which means they can't see us.
我们被断了退路
We are cut off.
是一窝被困住的老鼠
Rats in a barrel.
这就是大屠杀前的片刻宁静
This is the peace before the carnage.
人不会无缘无故死去!
People do not just die for no reason!
他们会死 是因为有人对他们做了什么事
They die because something was done to them by someone.
有个爱尔兰人拿着枪坐在那儿!
There's a Fenian sat over there with a bloody gun!
没人会来救我们 一切都完了
No-one's coming for us. This is the end.
你敢碰我的私人物品!
Don't you dare touch my possessions!
你想藏匿什么东西?
What have you got to hide?
一整个早上都在收拾内脏... 你胆子还真够大的
The whole morning, clearing up guts... you've got some right brass neck.
我们都被盯上了
We are all being hunted.
这个岛上还有其他人
There's someone else on this island,
等我找到他 我就让他做我手下第22个亡魂
and when I find him, I'm going to make him number 22.